Zhongjun (Mark) Jin

Contact

4945 Bob and Betty Beyster Building

Information

Phone: (765) 421-5014

2260 Hayward Street Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA E-mail: markjin@umich.edu, markjin1990@gmail.com

Website: https://markjin1990.github.io/

OBJECTIVES

Applying for an industrial research scientist / applied scientist / research engineer / software engineer position starting in summer 2020.

RESEARCH Interests

Build human-in-the-loop (interactive) data preparation systems (like cleaning, exploration, integration, etc.) to improve productivity of data scientists/analysts, programmers, and non-experts using techniques like inductive program synthesis, heuristics and machine learning guided combinatorial search, data profiling.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Aug. 2014 - May 2020

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science and Engineering

• Advisor: Prof. Michael Cafarella and Prof. H. V. Jagadish

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA

Aug. 2011 - May 2014

B.S. in Computer Science, Mathematics

Tianjin University, Tianjin, China

Aug. 2009 - Jul. 2011

Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SELECTED Professional EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA

Feb 2019 - May 2019

Research Intern (Mentored by Yeye He)

Designed and implemented a system (like the seminal FLASHFILL system) recommending string data transformation programs which standardize or normalize regular-expression-like data patterns for a given set of string data (like phone numbers, or dates) with heterogeneous data patterns. Unlike most existing systems, which synthesize programs in real time, the recommended programs in our system are learned offline from a large corpus of web data and of higher quality.

Trifacta, San Francisco, CA

May 2017 - Sep. 2017

Software Engineering Intern (Mentored by Sean Kandel, Michael Minar, and Prof. Joe Hellerstein) Designed and implemented CLX, an interactive data cleaning system. CLX 1) automatically identifies regular-expression-like data patterns for a given set of string data with heterogeneous data patterns for non-expert users to understand, and 2) suggests pattern-based transformation programs to unify various data patterns. The work was integrated to Trifacta Cloud Wrangler as a main feature in Aug 2018 and available at https://cloud.trifacta.com/.

Qualcomm, San Diego, CA

May 2013 - Aug. 2013

Software Engineering Intern

Add features to the test automation system in Qualcomm.

SELECTED Research **PROJECTS**

FOOFAH - Programming-By-Example System for Synthesizing Data Transformation Programs. [Python, CherryPy, Javascript, C++]

FOOFAH performs data transformation/cleaning through programming by examples (PBE), which requires little domain knowledge from non-expert users. It efficiently discovers a sequence of

parameterized data wrangling actions which guarantee to transform the raw data into the example form provided by the end user using a combinatorial search algorithm guided by the proposed distance metric customized for spreadsheets. The user interaction time is reduced by $\sim 60\%$ compared to the seminal **Wrangler** system. The system is open-sourced at https://github.com/umich-dbgroup/foofah/.

MITHRACOVERAGE - System for Investigating Population Bias for Intersectional Fairness. [Java, Maven, CherryPy, Javascript]

The system efficiently discovers under-represented/under-covered intersectional subgroups in a given dataset (e.g., a medical dataset may lack data records from a subgroup of "Hispanic women"), which may cause the problem of population bias. MITHRACOVERAGE also suggests a ranked list of subgroups in which the user could collect more data entries to remedy the above issue and ensure data fairness.

PRISM - Example-based SQL Query Synthesizer. [Java, Weka, Maven, MySQL]

The system infers SQL queries using imprecise and/or incomplete user examples from the target table the user desires from a relational database. The query discovery uses a bottom-up search-based algorithm and a filter-based validation process driven by a Bayesian network which reduces the overall number of query executions on the source database by $\sim 70\%$.

DEEPWRANGLER - Data Transformation Program Synthesizer Guided by a Neural Network. [Python, PyTorch]

Many existing Programming by Example data transformation systems require many examples from end users to find the transformation programs they actually desire. **DeepWrangler** leverages a neural network to guide the program synthesis algorithm to reduce the number of examples needed and therefore saves the user interaction time.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Christopher Baik, **Zhongjun Jin**, Michael Cafarella, and H. V. Jagadish, "Constructing Expressive Relational Queries with Dual-Specification Synthesis", in *CIDR* 2020.
- 2. **Zhongjun Jin**, Michael Cafarella, H. V. Jagadish, Sean Kandel, Michael Minar, and Joseph M. Hellerstein, "CLX: Towards verifiable PBE data transformation", in *EDBT* 2019.
- 3. **Zhongjun Jin**, Christopher Baik, Michael Cafarella, H. V. Jagadish, and Yuze Lou, "Demonstration of a Schema Mapping System Using Multiresolution Constraints", in *CIDR* 2019.
- 4. Abolfazl Asudeh, **Zhongjun Jin**, and H. V. Jagadish, "Assessing and Remedying Coverage for a Given Dataset", in *ICDE* 2019.
- 5. **Zhongjun Jin**, Michael R Anderson, Michael Cafarella, and H. V. Jagadish, "Foofah: Data Transformation By Example", in *SIGMOD* 2017.

Honors and Awards

- 1st Prize in "Systems, Software Engineering and Computer Science" session in *Michigan Engineering Graduate Symposium 2017 (EGS 2017) Graduate Research Contest*, 2017.
- Selected as "Best of Demos" at SIGMOD 2017.
- Sigmod Travel Award, 2017.
- University of Michigan Departmental PhD Fellowship, 2014.
- Outstanding Undergraduate Research Endeavor Award, Purdue Computer Science Dept. 2014
- Purdue Computer Science Neel Memorial Scholarship, 2013
- Purdue Computer Science Departmental Scholarship, 2012

INVITED TALKS

 "Intelligent Self-service Data Preparation: Problems and Solutions", 11/15/2018, Llamasoft Inc., USA.

SERVICE

• External Reviewer: SoCC'19